【海盗影院  出品】
-== http://www.hdmeiju.com ==-
新浪微博: @海盗美剧
大力士  蓝光收藏版
Hercules  Blu-ray Collectors' Edition
制 作: 海盗美剧
A HDmeiju Production
字 幕: 搜珍玉镜
Subs edited by Souzhenyujing
制 作: 寒 枫
Encoded by Hanfeng
很久以前 在遥远的古希腊时代
Long ago, in the faraway land of ancient Greece,
历史记载了 伟大的天神与英雄的辉煌事迹
there was a golden age of powerful gods and extraordinary heroes.
然而在众英雄当中最了不起的 就是伟大的海格力斯
And the greatest and strongest of all these heroes was the mighty Hercules.
要如何来界定真正的英雄呢?
But what is the measure of a true hero?
- 这就是我们要讲的故事  - 少听他胡扯
- That is what our story is... - Will you listen to him?
故事到他嘴里 八成会变成希腊的悲剧
He's makin' the story sound like some Greek tragedy.
- 放轻松点 好吗?  - 让我们来说吧 亲爱的
- Lighten up, dude. - We'll take it from here, darling.
请吧 女士们
You go, girl.
我们是缪司女神 负责掌管艺术 跟宣布谁是英雄
We are the Muses, goddesses of the arts and proclaimers of heroes.
像海格力斯这号英雄
Heroes like Hercules.
宝贝 你是说"帅哥力斯"
Honey, you mean "Hunk-ules."
我要唱首歌来赞美他
'd like to make some sweet music with him...
我们要说的故事 早在海格力斯出生以前 就已经发生了
Our story actually begins long before Hercules, many aeons ago.
地球混沌初开
Back when the world was new
这星球充满暴戾怨哀
The planet Earth was down on its luck
有一群凶狠怪兽 它们叫泰坦巨魔
And everywhere gigantic brutes called Titans ran amok
天地万物受害
It was a nasty place
痛苦和脏乱寸步难迈
There was a mess wherever you stepped
世界动乱 那地震火山不停在哭喊
Where chaos reigned and the earthquakes and volcanoes never slept
你说得对
Say it, girlfriend!
后来 天神宙斯
And then along came Zeus
- 用闪电来作战  - 打击
- He hurled his thunderbolt - He zapped
- 收拾怪物  - 他为民除害
- Locked those suckers in a vault - They're trapped
他英勇善战平息这动乱
And on his own stopped chaos in its tracks
你要去领悟
And that's the gospel truth
宙斯他完美拯救世界
The guy was too "Type A" to just relax
这星球获重生
And that's the world's first dish
对 宝贝
Yeah, baby.
宙斯年少掌管了万物
Zeus tamed the globe while still in his youth
这甜美滋味不可思议
Though, honey it may seem impossible
真理要领悟
That's the gospel truth
在奥林帕斯山 尽情享乐 笑语不断
On Mount Olympus life was neat and smooth as sweet vermouth
这甜美滋味不可思议
Although, honey it may seem impossible
真理要领悟
That's the gospel truth
片 名: 大力士
海格力斯
Hercules!
宝贝 你要乖哦
Behave yourself.
瞧瞧他
Look at this.
多可爱啊
Look how cute he is.
他真壮 跟他爸爸一样
He's strong like his dad.
嘿 新鲜的 新鲜的 大家靠边 大家小心靠边站
Excuse me! Hot stuff coming through! Excuse me. One side, Ares.
阿墨司 好美的花
Why, Hermes, they're lovely.
对啊 我找音乐之神特别安排的
Yeah, you know, I had Orpheus do the arrangement.
你喜不喜欢呢?
Isn't that too nutty?
这个派对气氛不错耶
Fabulous party. You know,
把水仙花神感动得又开始亲自己
I haven't seen this much love in a room since Narcissus discovered himself.
亲爱的 不能让宝宝玩那个
Dear, keep those away from the baby.
他不会伤到自己的
He won't hurt himself.
让孩子玩得开心点嘛
Let the kid have a little fun.
我谨代表犬子
On behalf of my son,
非常感谢各位送来的厚礼
I want to thank you all for your wonderful gifts!
那我们送什么呢?
What about our gift, dear?
让我想想 我们就... 好
Well, let's see here. We'll take... Yes.
先来点小羽毛 再来点低气压的云
A little cirrus and a touch of nimbostratus
然后混上一点圆形的云
and a dash of cumulus.
就叫它柏格斯
His name is Pegasus,
今后就是你的了 儿子
and he's all yours, son.
小心他的头
Mind his head.
他长得真小
He's so tiny.
我的儿子
My boy.
我的小海格力斯
My little Hercules.
真叫人感动
How sentimental.
该怎么形容才好?
You know, I haven't been this choked up
就像我上次吃鱼 被鱼骨头卡到了喉咙
since I got a hunk of moussaka caught in my throat!
噎得我都说不出话来
So is this an audience or a mosaic?
你好吗? 气色不错 衣服挺好
Hey, how you doin'? Lookin' good. Nice dress.
凯帝斯 你总算来了 地狱里的事情都顺利吧?
So, Hades, you finally made it. How are things in the underworld?
这... 很好啊 有点黑 有点闷
Well, they're just fine. You know, a little dark, a little gloomy.
老样子啦 不就是些死人
And, as always, hey, full of dead people.
能怎么样?
What are you gonna do?
就这小家伙啊 小宝贝
There's the little sunspot. Little snootchie.
我这有根棒棒糖
And here is a sucker for the little sucker, eh?
拿去吃吧 小傻瓜
Here you go. Ya just...
这个小子 真壮
Powerful little tyke.
好啦 凯帝斯 别逗宝宝了 去跟大伙乐一乐
Come on, Hades. Don't be such a stiff. Join the celebration!
嘿
Hey.
好是好 但是我可不像天上各位 这么悠哉悠哉
Love to, babe, but unlike you gods lounging about up here,
很不幸的是 我有要职在身
I regrettably have a full-time gig
而且这个工作 还是你派给我的呢 宙斯
that you, by the way, so charitably bestowed on me, Zeus.
所以 不了 很想 下次吧
So, can't. Love to, but can't.
你得放轻松 否则会累死的
You ought to slow down. You'll work yourself to death.
你会"累死"
Work yourself to death!
我幽默死了
I kill myself!
笑死算了 死了好喂狗
If only. If only.
你每个神都可以得罪 但就是不能得罪凯帝斯
If there's one god you don't want to get steamed up, it's Hades.
因为他一肚子的坏水
'Cause he had an evil plan.
他掌管那地狱
He ran the underworld
阴间幽魂他觉得无趣
But thought the dead were dull and uncouth
心地残忍 他手段毒辣
He was as mean as he was ruthless
这真理要领悟
And that's the gospel truth
无情无义 阴谋酝酿
He had a plan to shake things up
这真理要领悟
And that's the gospel truth
痛苦
Pain!
来了 我伟大的阴间大帝
Coming, your most lugubriousness.
慌张
Panic!
抱歉 我来处理
I'm sorry. I can handle it!
- 痛苦  - 还有慌张
- Pain! - And Panic!
- 向长官报到  - 向长官报到
- Reporting for duty! - Reporting for duty!
很好 很好
Fine, fine, fine.
如果命运之神来了 记得通知我
Just let me know the instant the Fates arrive.
她们到了
They're here.
什么? 已经来了 为什么不通知我?
What? The Fates are here, and you didn't tell me?
- 我们无能 是没用的虫子  - 我们无能 是没用的虫子
- We are worms! Worthless worms! - We are worms! Worthless worms!
开完会以后 麻烦你们两位提醒我 记得跟你们算帐
Memo to me, memo to me. Maim you after my meeting.
亲爱的 把那根掌管生命的线
Darling, hold that mortal's thread of life
给我拉直扯紧 好吗?
good and tight.
生意上门啦
Incoming!
已服务　五十亿　人
已服务五十亿零一人
女士们 很抱歉 我
Ladies! I am so sorry that I'm...
- 迟到  - 迟到  - 迟到
- Late! - Late! - Late!
- 我们早就知道  - 我们什么都知道
- We knew you would be. - We know everything.
- 过去  - 现在
- Past. - Present.
还有未来
And Future.
抽水马桶会大受欢迎
Indoor plumbing, it's gonna be big.
好 我参加一个庆生会 所以我忘了是什么时间
Great, great. Anyway, see, ladies, I was at this party, and I lost track of...
- 我们知道  - 我知道 你们知道
- We know! - Yeah. I know you know.
好 事情是这样的 宙斯
So here's the deal. Zeus,
伟大的天神 死巴着权力不放的那位仁兄 最近他生了个
Mr High and Mighty, Mr "Hey, you, get off of my cloud," now he has...
- 可爱的小壮丁  - 我们知道
- A bouncing baby brat. - We know!
我也知道 你们知道 我知道 你们知道 你们都知道
I know you know. I know. I got it. I got the concept.
现在我想问的是
So let me just ask.
这个小子会不会妨碍我霸占他老子的事业?
Is this kid gonna mess up my hostile takeover bid, or what?
你们说说看
What do you think?
好了 别说了 我们是不可以泄漏天机的
No, you don't. We're not supposed to reveal the future.
抱歉 换个说法
Wait. I'm sorry. Time out. Can I...
能不能请教你 你最近是不是
Can I ask you a question, by the way? Are you...
刚剪过头发? 看起来真是很棒
Did you cut your hair or something? You look fabulous.
我是说 看起来比死了还恐怖
I mean, you look like a Fate worse than death.
- 恶心死了  - 活的 快躲开
- Gross! - It's blinkin'!
女士们 拜托
Ladies, please.
我的命运 就在你们可爱的手里
My fate is in your lovely hands.
- 啊  - 好吧
- Yeah! - All right.
十八年后的今天
In 18 years precisely,
星球会运转到一种很和谐的境界
the planets will align ever so nicely.
又作诗了
Verse.
想行动就要快一点了
The time to act will be at hand.
放了泰坦巨魔 他们是你的帮手
Unleash the Titans, your monstrous band.
啊 好
Good, good.
这样子骄傲的宙斯 将会完全垮台
Then the once-proud Zeus will finally fall,
而你 凯帝斯 将会君临天下
and you, Hades, will rule all!
对 凯帝斯将君临天下
Yes! Hades rules!
但是有一件事我要提醒你
A word of caution to this tale.
什么?
Excuse me?
如果海格力斯反击 你就完了
Should Hercules fight, you will fail.
他敢
What?
好 没事没事 我很镇静 我没事
Okay, fine, fine. I'm cool. I'm fine.
痛苦 慌张 让你们猜一个小谜语
Pain? Panic? Got a little riddle for ya.
如何才能杀了一个神?
How do you kill a god?
- 不知道  - 不行的 神是不会死的
- I do not know! - You can't. They're immortal?
答对了 神是不会死的
Bingo! They're immortal.
所以 必须先把那小子 变成凡人
So, first you got to turn the little sunspot mortal.
什么声音啊?
What? What is it?
- 孩子  - 孩子
- The baby! - The baby!
海格力斯
Hercules!
不
No!
我们干了件蠢事
Now we did it!
我们成了宙斯的箭靶了
Zeus is gonna use us for target practice!
把孩子抱紧了 慌张
Just hang onto the kid, Panic.
快
Hurry!
快把孩子做了 交差了事 好吗?
Let's just kill the kid and get it over with, okay?
你别急 给他来点特殊配方
Here you go, kid. A little Grecian formula.
快看 他在改变 我们可以动手了吗?
Look at that! He's changing. Can we do it now?
不 不行 他得把整瓶喝完才行 一滴都不能剩
No, he has to drink the whole potion. Every last drop.
是谁啊?
Who's there?
阿尔克墨涅(Alcmene): 希腊神话中大力神赫拉克勒斯(Heracles)之母
你看 在这里哦
Alcmene, over here.
真叫人心疼啊
You poor thing.
- 乖宝贝  - 有人在这儿吗?
- Don't cry. - Is anybody there?
- 可以了吗?  - 动手
- Now? - Now.
他八成是个弃婴
Well, he must have been abandoned.
安菲特律翁(Amphitryon): 希腊神话中赫拉克勒斯的养父
老伴啊 多年以来
Amphitryon, for so many years
我们一直向神明祈求 赐给我们一个孩子
we've prayed to the gods to bless us with a child.
- 或许他们听到祈祷了  - 嗯 很有可能
- Perhaps they've answered our prayers. - Perhaps they have.
"海格力斯"
"Hercules"?
完蛋了
Help, help, help!
如果事情被凯帝斯发现 他会宰了我们的
Hades is gonna kill us when he finds out what happened.
你是说 如果被他发现
You mean, if he finds out.
他当然会发...
Of course he's gonna...
"如果" 好词耶
If. If is good.
真是悲剧
It was tragic.
宙斯带领众神疯狂地搜寻
Zeus led all the gods on a frantic search.
当他们找到婴儿的时候 一切都迟了
But by the time they found the baby, it was too late.
小海格变凡人
Young Herc was mortal now
还好他没喝最后一滴
But since he did not drink the last drop
他保存了他的神力
He still retained his godlike strength
那守护神眷恋
So thank his lucky stars
继续说
Tell it, girl.
宙斯 海娜流泪
But Zeus and Hera wept
因为儿子不能再回家
Because their son could never come home
默默地看着亲爱宝贝 茁壮在远方
They'd have to watch their precious baby grow up from afar
凯帝斯坏心肠
Though Hades' horrid plan
小海格力斯还未长大
Was hatched before Herc cut his first tooth
他日复一日变强壮
The boy grew stronger every day
这真理要领悟
And that's the gospel truth
真理领悟
The gospel truth
海格力斯 慢一点
Hercules, slow down!
小心
Look out!
抱歉 老兄
S-S-Sorry, guys.
- 没长眼睛啊  - 瞎胡闹
- Hey, watch where you're goin'. - Sunday driver!
谢谢你 儿子
Thanks, son.
当老潘把脚给扭伤的时候 我还以为咱们完蛋了呢
When old Penelope twisted her ankle back there, I thought we were done for.
别担心 爸
No problem, Pop.
菲迪亚斯(Phideas 活动时期约公元前490~前430): 雅典雕刻家
等一等 先别卸货 我先跟菲底阿斯谈妥价钱
Don't-don't-don't unload just yet. First, I have to finagle with Phideas.
好的
Okay.
对不起 老潘
Sorry, Penelope.
你听好 海格力斯 这一次你只要
Now, Hercules, this time, please just...
我知道 我知道
I know. I know.
待在马车边
Stay by the cart.
我的乖儿子
That's my boy.
哦 我的天哪
Oh, my goodness.
小心
Careful!
- 真谢谢你  - 不客气
- Why, thank you. - No problem.
海格力斯
Why, Hercules!
是... 是你
I-l-It's you!
- 我来帮你拿  - 不 不 我没事
- Let me, let me help you with that. - No, no, no, no, no. I got it!
我可以 你去忙吧
I'm fine. You just run along.
- 你确定?  我确定
- Are you sure? - Yes.
确定
Absolutely.
嘿 丢给我
Yo! Give it here!
嗨 你们还需要人吗?
Hey, you need an extra guy?
抱歉 小海
Sorry, Herc.
我们已经有五个人了 队员数目必须是双数才行
We already got five, and we want to keep it an even number.
等一等 五又不是双数
Hey, wait a second. Five isn't an even...
- 再见  - 小怪物
- See ya, Herc. - What a geek!
- 破坏力超强  - 我们以后叫他"逊格力斯"
- Destructo Boy. - Maybe we should call him "Jerkules."
小心
Heads up!
好 我来接
I-I got it!
不要接
No! Stop!
完了
No.
我抓到了
It's okay.
别倒
Hey!
- 儿子  - 爸 我马上就回来
- Son! - Hang on, Pop! Be right back!
不 不 不 不 不
Oh, my! No! Don't! No, no, no, no!
No, no, no, no, no, no!
小心
Watch out!
你真行耶 "逊格力斯"
Nice catch, Jerkules.
儿子
Son...
我已经无法再忍受下去了 安斐翁
This is the last straw, Amphitryon!
那个孩子简直是个疯子
That boy is a menace!
正常人跟他待在一起是很危险的
He's too dangerous to be around normal people!
他一点恶意都没有 他还年轻
He didn't mean any harm. He's just a kid.
不知道如何控制他的力气
He just can't control his strength.
我警告你
I'm warning you.
你最好... 最好让这怪物滚远一点
You keep that-that-that freak away from here!
对啊 怪物 滚远一点啊
Freak! Yeah, go away!
不要难过了 别让那些人说的话影响你
Son, you shouldn't let those things they said back there get to you.
但是他们说得对 我的确是个怪物 我想要跟他们一样啊
But, Pop, they're right. I-I am a freak. I-I try to fit in. I really do.
但老是失败
I just can't.
有的时候 我觉得 自己根本就不属于这里
Sometimes I feel like... like I really don't belong here,
我好像是 天外飞来的
like I'm supposed to be someplace else.
海格力斯 儿子
Hercules, son...
我知道我很呆啦
I know it doesn't make any sense.
我有一个梦 在遥远天际
I have often dreamed of a far off place
人们衷心期盼 盼望我的来临
Where a great, warm welcome will be waiting for me
面对那人群 拥抱着欢迎
Where the crowds will cheer when they see my face
脑海翻腾不已 指引那里属于你
And a voice keeps sayin' this is where I'm meant to be
我要去追寻
I will find my way
不怕一路艰辛
I can go the distance
我到达目的
I'll be there someday
我意志坚定
If I can be strong
我的每一步
I know every mile
勇敢往前行
Will be worth my while
我能够再回到那属于我的
I would go most anywhere to feel like I
故乡
Belong
海格力斯
Hercules,
有件事 你妈妈跟我一直想告诉你
there's something your mother and I have been meaning to tell ya.
你们发现了我 那我是从哪儿来的?
But if you found me, then where did I come from?
为什么他们不要我?
Why was I left here?
这个 是我们在你脖子上发现的
This was around your neck when we found you.
这是代表神明的记号
It's the symbol of the gods.
这就对了 你不懂吗? 或许我能找到答案
This is it! Don't you see? Maybe they have the answers!
我要去宙斯庙问一下
I'll go to the temple of Zeus and...
爸 妈
Ma, Pop,
你们是世上最好的父母 但是
you're the greatest parents anyone could have, but...
我要查明身世
I-I gotta know.
我要去追寻
I am on my way
不怕一路艰辛
I can go the distance
虽然路遥远
I don't care how far
我意志坚定
Somehow, I'll be strong
我的每一步
I know every mile
勇敢往前行
Will be worth my while
我能够再回到
I would go most anywhere
那属于我的故乡
To find where I belong
伟大的宙斯
Mighty Zeus,
请求你 听我虔诚的祈祷
please, hear me and answer my prayer.
我要知道
I need to know.
我是谁
Who am I?
我是从哪里来的
Where do I belong?
我的孩子
My boy.
我的小海格力斯
My little Hercules.
嘿 嘿 嘿 小子
Hey, hey, hey. Hold on, kiddo!
你跑什么跑
What's your hurry?
咱们父子分别这么多年 这就是你给爸爸的见面礼?
After all these years, is this the kind of hello you give your father?
爸... 爸爸?
F-F-Father?
你不知道你有个名人爸爸吗 孩子?
Didn't know you had a famous father, did you?
开心吗?
Surprise!
看你长得多好
Look how you've grown.
你的眼睛跟你妈妈那么美 下巴就像我一样性格
Why, you've got your mother's beautiful eyes and my strong chin.
我实在不明白
I don't understand.
如果你是我爸爸 那我不就是
If you're my father, that would make me a...
- 一个神  - 神
- A god. - A god.
一个神
A god!
儿子 你年纪已经够大了
Hey, you wanted answers,
你想知道什么我都可以告诉你
and by thunder, you're old enough now to know the truth.
你为什么把我丢在凡间? 你不想要我吗?
But why did you leave me on Earth? Didn't you want me?
我们当然要你
Of course we did.
你妈跟我是那么全心全意爱着你
Your mother and I loved you with all our hearts.
但是有人把你偷走了 而且把你变成了凡人
Someone stole you from us and turned you mortal,
只有神明才能住在奥林帕斯山
and only gods can live on Mount Olympus.
你一点办法都没有?
And you can't do a thing?
我没有 海格力斯 但你有
I can't, Hercules, but you can.
真的? 怎么做? 我完全配合
R-Really? W-What? I'll do anything.
如果你在凡间能够证明自己是真正的英雄
Hercules, if you can prove yourself a true hero on Earth,
你就能变回成神
your godhood will be restored!
真正的英雄 好耶
A true hero. Great!
但是怎么样才能成为真正的英雄?
Exactly how do you become a true hero?
菲罗克忒忒斯(Philoctetes): 希腊传说中的英雄 在特洛伊战争后期起了决定性的作用
首先 你得找到菲洛斯 他会训练英雄
First, you must seek out Philoctetes, the trainer of heroes.
找到菲洛斯 好 我就
Seek out Philoctetes. Right. I'll...
等一下 你别急啊
Hold your horses!
我想起来了
Which reminds me.
你可能不认得柏格斯了 你们两个可是青梅竹马哦
You probably don't remember Pegasus, but you two go way back, son.
柏格斯
Pegasus!
它还算不错 四肢发达 头脑简单
He's a magnificent horse with the brain of a bird.
我要找到菲洛斯 成为真正的英雄
I'll find Philoctetes, become a true hero.
你要勇往直前
That's the spirit!
我不会让你失望的 爸爸
I won't let you down, Father!
祝你好运了 儿子
Good luck, son.
我打败阻碍
I will beat the odds
不怕一路艰辛
I can go the distance
我要去追寻
I will face the world
勇敢往前闯
Fearless, proud and strong
我荣耀神明
I will please the gods
不怕一路艰辛
I can go the distance
我要拥抱英雄欢迎在我的
Till I find my hero's welcome right where I
故乡
Belong
你确定是这里吗?
You sure this is the right place?
怎么啦? 小家伙 被卡住啦?
W-What's the matter, little guy? You stuck?
嘿 放开我 小子
Hey, butt out, buddy!
美女们 别跑 别跑 快回来 快回来
Girls! Stop! Stop! Come back, come back, come back.
- 美女 看到你们我腿都软了  - 哼
- They can't keep their hands off me. - Hey!
看什么看 你没见过半人半羊吗?
What's the matter? You never seen a satyr before?
没有 我们正在找一个人
No. Can you help us?
他的名字叫做菲洛斯
We're looking for someone called Philoctetes.
叫我阿菲
Call me Phil.
阿菲
Phil!
哇 真高兴见到你 我是海格力斯
Boy, am I glad to meet you! I'm Hercules.
它是柏格斯
This is Pegasus.
畜牲 恶心死了
Animals! Disgusting!
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
我想成为英雄 一个真正的英雄
I want to become a hero, a true hero.
- 抱歉 小子 无能为力  - 等等
- Sorry, kid. Can't help ya. - Wait!
对不起
Sorry.
- 为什么?  - 一句话 我已经退休了
- Why not? - Two words, I am retired.
我真的想当英雄
Look, I gotta do this.
你难道没有过梦想?
Haven't you ever had a dream,
或者很渴望能够完成一件事?
something you wanted so bad you'd do anything?
小子 进来吧 让你看些东西
Kid, come inside. I want to show you something.
小心 这些全都是真正的古董
Watch it! That was part of the mast of the Argo.
- 真的古董  - 嗯
- The Argo? - Yeah.
是谁让杰生成为航海英雄的?
Who do you think taught Jason how to sail?
埃及艳后吗?
Cleopatra?
这些英雄全是我训练出来的
I trained all those would-be heroes.
奥迪塞斯 勃尔塞斯 迪斯尤斯 都是斯啊斯的
Odysseus, Perseus, Theseus. A lot of "yeuseus."
可惜啊 每一个都是庸才 每一个都会让我失望透顶
And every single one of those bums let me down flatter than a discus.
没有一个能坚持到底
None of 'em could go the distance.
最后 来了个阿奇利斯
And then there was Achilles.
总算是有个家伙样样都行了 跑得稳 跑得快
Now, there was a guy who had it all, the build, the foot speed.
能揍人 能挨人揍 有旺盛的战斗力
He could jab, he could take a hit, he could keep on comin'.
可惜他的脚跟不争气
But that furshlugginer heel of his!
只对他的脚跟轻轻一弹 他就"轰"
He barely gets nicked there once and kaboom!
玩完了
He's history.
没错 我有过梦想
Yeah, I had a dream once.
我梦想自己训练出来空前绝后的大英雄
I dreamed I was gonna train the greatest hero there ever was.
伟大到 连众神都会在天上为他立一个星座 只要看到那个星座
So great, the gods would hang a picture of him in the stars all across the sky,
人们就会说 那是阿菲的徒弟
and people would say, "That's Phil's boy."
没错
That's right.
哎呀 只有毛头小子才会做梦
But dreams are for rookies.
我已经老得禁不起失望的打击了
A guy can only take so much disappointment.
我跟其他人是不一样的 阿菲
But I'm different than those other guys, Phil!
我能够坚持到底 我证明给你看
I can go the distance. Come on. I'll show you.
老天啊 你真不死心
Geez! You don't give up, do ya?
看好哦
Watch this.
我的妈呀
Holy Hera.
或许 他有可能 不 别骗自己了
You know, maybe if I... No! Snap out of it!
我太老了 训练不出真英雄来了
I'm too old to get mixed up in this stuff again.
如果我不能成为真正的英雄 我就不能回到我爸爸宙斯身边了
But if I don't become a true hero, I'll never be able to rejoin my father, Zeus.
等等
Hold it!
宙斯是你爸爸 对不对?
Zeus is your father, right?
宙斯 那个大个儿 是你老子?
Zeus. The big guy. He's your daddy.
那位闪电老兄
Mr Lightning Bolts!
说故事给我听 爸爸
Read me a book, would ya, Da-da?
很久很久以前
Zeus! "Once upon a time..."
这是真的
It's the truth!
拜托
Please!
你想成为一个英雄 是吗?
So you wanna be a hero, kid
呜滴嘟
Well, whoop-de-do
我经验老道
I have been around the block before
训练无数的笨蛋就像你
With blockheads just like you
往事不堪回首 失望痛苦
Each and every one a disappointment
和伤心无助把泪流
Pain for which there ain't no ointment
我不愿再复出 管他宙斯儿子
So much for excuses though a kid of "Zeus" is
休想叫我心情沉谷底
Askin' me to jump into the fray
我答案 一句话
My answer is two words
好吧
Okay.
- 你答应了  - 你赢了
- You mean you'll do it? - You win.
- 你不会后悔的  - 天啊
- You won't be sorry, Phil. - Oh, gods.
什么时候开始? 现在吗?
So when do we start? Can we start now?
我放弃希望 我热情不再燃烧
I'd given up hope that someone would come along
不会有徒弟为我努力夺锦标
A fella who'd ring the bell for once Not the gong
不再有冠军杯
The kind who wins trophies
不愿虚心求教
Won't settle for low fees
哪怕奖金他也不要
At least semipro fees
我脸都绿了
But, no, I get the greenhorn
我已经退休数十年 野心不再
I've been out to pasture, pal. My ambition gone
享受那闲云野鹤慵懒的生活
Content to spend lazy days and to graze my lawn
但是你需要教练
But you need an advisor
有智慧 有经验
A satyr, but wiser
有营销的概念 有...
A good merchandiser and...
我的胃溃疡
There goes my ulcer
我唯一的希望 这希望是你
I'm down to one last hope and I hope it's you
虽然你的条件并不合我意
Though, kid, you're not exactly a dream come true
我训练过土蛋 从没有结果
I trained enough turkeys who never came through
你是我希望 一定要成功
You're my one last hope. So you'll have to do
规则第六条
Rule number six.
当你搭救一位高贵小姐 记得要轻手轻脚
When rescuing a damsel, always handle with care.
不
No!
规则第九十五条 要专心
Rule number 95, kid. Concentrate!
规则第九十六条
Rule number 96.
瞄准
Aim!
一定要设定目标 不达目的永不停息
Demigods have faced the odds and ended up a mockery
不要相信那神话 传奇故事不能帮你
Don't believe the stories that you read on all the crockery
做个真正英雄 你必须去卖命
To be a true hero, kid, is a dying art
像一幅旷世巨作
Like paintin' a masterpiece
用内心作画
It's a work of heart
它不是靠蛮力
It takes more than sinew
靠心灵的力量
Comes down to what's in you
你必须不断地成长
You have to continue to grow
这样还差不多
Now, that's more like it!
我唯一的希望寄托你身上
I'm down to one last shot And my last high note
在我驾鹤西归以前去战斗
Before that blasted underworld gets my goat
你是我的梦想
My dreams are on you, kid
别令我失望
Go make 'em come true
快爬上颠峰
Climb that uphill slope
你就是人中之龙
Keep pushin' that envelope
你是我希望
You're my one last hope
你一定要成功
And, kid, it's up to you
耶
Yeah!
过不过瘾啊?
Did you see that?
下一站 奥林帕斯山
Next stop, Olympus.
好 但是慢慢来 冠军
All right, just take it easy, champ.
我准备好了 我想离开这个小岛
I am ready. I want to get off this island.
我想去打怪兽
I want to see battles and monsters.
去救美女
Rescue some damsels.
就是 去当英雄啊
You know, heroic stuff.
- 这个...  - 拜托 阿菲
- Well... - Come on! Phil!
好吧 好吧 你想试试身手吗? 准备走吧 孩子
Well, okay. Okay, you want a road test? Saddle up, kid.
第比斯(Thebes): 希腊雅典西北维奥蒂亚州主要城市 古希腊重要城市和强国
我们去锡比斯
We're going to Thebes!
- 锡比斯有什么?  - 很多问题
- So what's in Thebes? - A lot of problems.
又大又乱的城市 很适合建立知名度
It's a big, tough town. Good place to start buildin' a rep.
英雄救美 落难的大家闺秀
Sounds like your basic DID, Damsel in Distress.
你逃不掉的 小甜心
Not so fast, sweetheart.
我警告你 涅修斯 放我下来 不然我就
I swear, Nessus. Put me down or I'll...
我喜欢凶婆子
I like 'em fiery!
孩子 要记住
Now, remember, kid.
首先要分析状况
First, analyse the situation.
想想清楚 不要一头就栽进去
Don't just barrel in there without thinking.
我真是教育失败
He's losin' points for this!
- 放我...  - 住手
- You don't know what you're... - Halt!
闪一边去 臭小子
Step aside, two legs.
抱歉 这位 嗯 先生
Pardon me, my good, uh, uh, sir.
我要求你把这位
I'll have to ask you to release that young...
- 最好少管闲事  - 小姐
- Keep movin', junior. - Lady.
但是 你不是 落难的大家闺秀?
But you... Aren't you a damsel in distress?
我是大家闺秀 我也有难
I'm a damsel, I'm in distress.
但是我可以应付 再见啦
I can handle this. Have a nice day.
小姐 你可能还不清楚 你已经陷入了危险
Ma'am, I'm afraid you may be too close to the situation to realise...
- 你在干什么? 快拔剑啊  - 拔剑 对 对
- What are you doin'? Get your sword! - Sword. Right, right.
规则第十五条 英雄有武器才有力量
Rule number 15, a hero is only as good as his weapon!
不 不 不 他一定要靠自己
Hold it! Hold on! He's gotta do it on his own.
快点 小子 专心一点
Come on, kid! Concentrate!
不会用脑袋啊
Use your head!
好耶 不赖 小子
All right! Not bad, kid!
虽然不合我意 但可以接受
Not exactly what I had in mind, but not bad.
小姐 真是对不起啊 我太粗鲁了
Miss, I'm, I'm really sorry. That was dumb.
对
Yeah.
失陪
Excuse me.
表现优异 真是优秀啊
Nice work! Excelente!
咱们的神奇小子玩真的啊
Is Wonderboy here for real?
你在胡扯什么? 他当然是玩真的
What are you talkin' about? Of course he's real.
顺便告诉你 小甜甜 我也是玩真的
And by the way, sweet cheeks, I'm real, too.
- 我表现得怎么样?  - 先别得意 菜鸟
- How was that, Phil? - Rein it in, rookie.
这种小场面的比赛 犯点小错倒是无所谓
You can get away with mistakes like those in the minor decathlons,
但是到大场面就不行了
but this is the big leagues!
可是我打败他了 不是吗?
At least I beat him, didn't I?
下一次 不要因为女人跟你抛个媚眼就松了防线
Next time, don't let your guard down because of a pair of big goo-goo eyes!
我不是一直告诉你 必须要集中注意力 而你...
It's like I keep tellin' ya. You gotta stay focused, and... You...
你还 好吗? 小姐
Are you, uh, all right, Miss, uh...
蜜格拉 我的朋友都叫我蜜儿 虽然我没什么朋友
Megara. My friends call me Meg. At least, they would if I had any friends.
对了 你壮得跟牛一样 别人都是怎么叫你的?
So did they give you a name along with all those rippling pectorals?
我叫...
Uh, uh, uh, I'm, um...
你都是这样说话的吗?
Are you always this articulate?
海格力斯 我叫海格力斯
Hercules. My... My name is Hercules.
海格 哇 应该叫你神奇小子
Hercules. I think I prefer Wonderboy.
那.. 你是怎么惹上那个...
So, how-how-how'd you get mixed up with the...
那个怪物? 男人老是
Pinhead with hooves? Well, you know how men are.
把"不"当成"好" 叫他们滚开 他们还以为是"抱紧我"
They think that "No" means "Yes," and "Get lost" means "Take me, I'm yours."
别担心 那个矮冬瓜会教你
Don't worry. Shorty here can explain it to ya later.
谢谢你了 海格 你让我终生难忘
Well, thanks for everything, Herc. It's been a real slice.
等等 我可以送你一程吗?
Wait! Can we give you a ride?
你的小马儿好像不太喜欢我
I don't think your pinto likes me very much.
柏格斯? 怎么会呢? 它高兴都来不及呢
Pegasus? No. Don't be silly. He'd be more than happy to...
我不会有事的 我是个坚强的女孩 我一向都是单打独斗
I'll be all right. I'm a big, tough girl. I tie my own sandals and everything.
拜拜 神奇小子
Bye-bye, Wonderboy.
拜
Bye.
她棒透了 阿菲 对不对?
She's something. Isn't she, Phil?
是啊 是啊 她棒透了
Yeah. Yeah. She's really something.
她根本就讨厌透了
A real pain in the patella!
海格 醒醒吧 听到请回答 听到请回答
Earth to Herc! Come in, Herc! Come in, Herc!
我们还有事情要做呢
We got a job to do, remember?
我们得去锡比斯
Thebes is still waitin'.
对啊 对啊 我知道
Yeah. Yeah. I know.
好可爱
How cute.
两只小老鼠 在找迪士尼乐园啊?
A couple of rodents looking for a theme park.
你说谁是老鼠啊? 小姐 我是兔子
Who you callin' a rodent, sister? I'm a bunny!
我是地鼠
And I'm his gopher.
什么东西这么臭啊
I thought I smelled a rat.
小蜜儿
Meg?
说到曹操
Speak of the devil.
蜜儿 我的小百花 小黄莺 小疯子蜜儿
Meg, my little flower, my little bird, my little nut, Meg.
这儿到底发生什么事了?
What exactly happened here?
我还以为你已经说服河神
I thought you were gonna persuade the river guardian
替我未来的计划尽点力
to join my team for the uprising,
我好像还缺少个看河的人
and here I am, kind of river guardian-less.
我已经尽力了 但是他提出的要求 实在令我难以接受
I gave it my best shot, but he made me an offer I had to refuse.
那好 你休想我会替你减刑两年
Fine. So, instead of subtracting two years from your sentence,
我会加两年 懂吧?
hey, I'm gonna add two on, okay?
你把事情搞砸了
Give that your best shot.
那不是我的错 全是那个神奇小子海格力斯害的
It wasn't my fault. It was this Wonderboy, Hercules.
海格力斯 这个名字听起来挺耳熟的
Hercules? Why does that name ring a bell?
好像听过 我们是不是欠他钱?
I don't know. Maybe we owe him money?
- 蜜儿 麻烦再说一遍那个名字  - 海格力斯
- What was that name again? - Hercules.
他演出全本的英雄救美
He comes on with this big, innocent farm boy routine,
不幸还是被我看穿他的伎俩
but I could see through that in a Peloponnesian minute.
等一等
Wait a minute.
海格力斯不就是那小鬼 我们应该...
Wasn't Hercules the name of that kid we were supposed to...
- 我的妈呀  - 我的妈呀
- Oh, my gods! - Oh, my gods!
快溜
Run for it!
你们把他解决了?
So you took care of him, huh?
那小子死了
Dead as a door nail.
你们不是这样子告诉我的?
Weren't those your exact words?
可能是另一个海格力斯
This might be a different Hercules.
是啊 很多男孩都喜欢叫海格力斯这个名字
Yeah! I mean, Hercules is a very popular name nowadays!
记得吗? 早几年 很多男生都喜欢叫志明
Remember, like, a few years ago, every other boy was named Jason,
很多女生都喜欢叫春娇
and the girls were all named Brittany?
我正准备重新安排宇宙的顺序
I'm about to rearrange the cosmos,
没想到 那唯一能破坏我计划的人 竟然还好好地在这儿英雄救美
and the one schlemiel who can louse it up is waltzing around in the woods!
等等 老大
Wait. Wait, big guy.
- 我们还是能让他变成狗熊啊  - 说得对
- We can still cut in on his waltzing. - That's right!
至少他成了凡人 这挺好的
And at least we made him mortal. That's a good thing.
不是吗?
Didn't we?
算你们三个命大
Fortunately for the three of you,
还有机会将功赎罪 去把这个错误纠正过来
we still have time to correct this rather egregious oversight.
这一次呢 不准失手
And this time, no foul-ups.
- 大城市耶  - 大城市里全是麻烦
- Is that all one town? - One town, a million troubles.
这就是锡比斯 外号大橄榄
The one and only Thebes. The Big Olive itself.
如果在这儿混得开 就可以混遍全世界了
If you can make it there, you can make it anywhere.
跟着我走 小子 城市是个很危险的地方
Stick with me, kid. This city is a dangerous place.
- 你走路不长眼睛啊  - 嘿 没看见我在走路啊
- Look where you're goin', numbskull! - Hey, I'm walkin' here!
怎么样? 见识到了吧 一群疯子
You see what I mean? I'm tellin' you, wackos.
烧饼 烧饼 好吃的烧饼
Pitta bread. Pitta bread. Get your pitta bread here.
嘿 老兄
Hey, Mack.
- 你要买一只手表吗?  - 他不想买 可以吧?
- You wanna buy a sundial? - He's not interested, all right?
快走 孩子
Come on, kid.
末日到了 你没感觉吗?
The end is coming! Can't you feel it?
有有有 谢谢你告诉我 好 我们会认真思考的
Yes, yes. Thank you for the info. Yes. We'll ponder that for a while.
你专心看路
Just stare at the sidewalk. Come on.
别跟生人乱抛媚眼 这里的人都有点疯
Don't make eye contact. People here are nuts.
因为他们整天都活在混乱当中
That's because they live in a city of turmoil.
相信我 小子
Trust me, kid.
他们需要的就是你这种人
You're gonna be just what the doctor ordered.
真是个悲剧啊 这场大火夺走了我所有的东西
It was tragic! We lost everything in the fire.
全没了 我剩下的只有小雪球
Everything except old Snowball here.
大火是在地震之前 还是之后呢?
Now, were the fires before or after the earthquake?
是在地震之后发生的
They were after the earthquake. I remember.
是在淹水之前
But before the flood.
我实在不想提这里的犯罪率
Don't even get me started on the crime rate.
锡比斯城的治安 恶化得相当迅速
Thebes has certainly gone downhill in a hurry.
我也知道啊
Tell me about it.
要不了多久就会有一个怪物
It seems like every time I turn around,
来这儿大肆破坏一番
there's some new monster wreaking havoc and I...
就差没被蝗虫侵略过
All we need now is a plague of locusts.
我受不了啦  我要搬去斯巴达
That's it! I'm movin' to Sparta!
对不起
Excuse me.
各位 这个城市似乎需要一位... 英雄
It, uh... seems to me that what you folks need is a hero.
是吗? 你是谁?
Yeah, and who are you?
我是海格力斯 而且我正好就是... 英雄
I'm Hercules, and, uh... I happen to be a hero.
- 你真的是吗?  - 英雄
- Is that so? - A hero!
- 你救过别的地方吗?  - 不 好像没有 可是
- Have you ever saved a town before? - No. Not exactly, but I...
你阻止过任何天然的灾害吗?
Have you ever reversed a natural disaster?
这个 嗯 没有
Well, uh, no.
你们看 又来了一个想骗钱的人
Listen to this. He's just another chariot chaser.
- 我们不需要你  - 就是嘛
- This we need. - That's a laugh.
你们这些笨蛋难道不懂吗?
Don't you pea brains get it?
这孩子是真正的英雄
This kid is the genuine article.
这个半人半羊的家伙是阿奇利斯的教练
Hey, isn't that the goat-man who trained Achilles?
小心一点 朋友
Watch it, pal.
是啊 没错
Yeah, you're right.
什么本领你都教给他了
Hey, nice job on those heels!
就是忘了脚丫子
Ya missed a spot!
我宰了你 敢笑我
I got your heel right here!
我非得教训你这自以为是的家伙
I'll wipe that stupid grin off your face! You...
阿菲 阿菲 阿菲
Hey, Phil! Phil! Phil! Take it easy. Phil.
你疯啦?
What are you, crazy?
年轻人 我们要的是真正的英雄 不是业余的
Young man, we need a professional hero, not an amateur.
喂 别走啊
Well, wait. Stop!
我可以证明我是个英雄 他们却不肯给我机会
How am I supposed to prove myself a hero if nobody will give me a chance?
会有机会的
You'll get your chance.
最好能来个天灾或是人祸
You just need some kind of catastrophe or disaster.
拜托
Please.
救命啊 拜托 有一个可怕的意外
Help! Please! There's been a terrible accident!
- 蜜儿  - 说到这天灾
- Meg? - Speakin' of disasters.
神奇小子 海格力斯 谢天谢地
Wonderboy! Hercules! Thank goodness!
这... 怎么回事啊?
Wha-Wha-What's wrong?
就在城外面 有两个小男孩在峡谷那里玩
Outside of town, two little boys. They were playing in the gorge.
有... 有一块大石头掉下来压到他们
Th-There was this terrible rockslide.
- 好可怕哦  - 小孩? 被压到了
- They're trapped! - Kids? Trapped?
阿菲 这太棒了
Phil, this is great!
你总算逮到机会了 对吧?
You're really choked up about this, aren't ya?
快啊
Come on!
不 不行啊 我有... 我有惧高症
No, I... You don't... I-I have this terrible fear of heights!
我马上就到
I'm right behind ya, kid!
我真的追不上你
I'm way behind ya, kid.
呼吸有点困难
I got a fur wedgie.
- 你还好吧?  - 我没事
- Are you okay? - I'll be fine.
趁我还没吐赶快放我下来
Just get me down before I ruin the upholstery.
- 救命 我不能呼吸了  - 快点哪
- Help! I can't breathe! - Hurry!
- 救我们出去  - 我们快闷死了
- Get us out! - We're suffocating!
快找救兵来啊
Somebody call IX-l-I!
别紧张 你们不会有事的
Easy, fellas. You'll be all right.
- 我们真的撑不下去了  - 快救我们 我们快要被压烂了
- We can't last much longer! - Get us out before we get crushed!
- 你们还好吧?  - 我们已经没事了
- How you boys doin'? - We're okay now.
天啊 先生 你真的好壮哦
Jeepers, mister. You're really strong.
下一次 记得千万要小心点 好吗? 小朋友
Well, try to be a little more careful next time, okay, kids?
我们一定会的
We sure will.
真无辜 小朋友
A stirring performance, boys.
我好感动
I was really moved.
"天啊 先生"
"Jeepers, mister"?
我只不过装得一脸无辜
I was going for innocence.
为我们的女主角欢呼一下吧
And, hey, two thumbs way, way up for our leading lady.
小妖精 还真嗲
What a dish. What a doll.
趁现在还来得及 你快走吧
Get outta there, you big lug, while you still can.
阿菲 怎么样?
Phil, I did great.
他们都鼓掌了 对吧
They even applauded, sort of.
我不想浇你的冷水 那不是鼓掌的声音
I hate to burst your bubble, kid, but that ain't applause.
天... 天啊 阿菲 这什么东西啊?
Ph-Ph-Ph-Phil? What do you call that thing?
一句话
Two words.
快逃啊
Am-scray!
精彩的好戏开始咯
Let's get ready to rumble!
对 绕它转 绕它转
That's it. Dance around! Dance around!
小心牙齿 小心牙齿 别停下来 出拳 出拳
Watch the teeth. Watch the teeth. Keep going. Come on. Come on.
出左拳 出左拳 是左手的拳头
Lead with your left. Lead with your left! Your other left!
好棒 好棒 帅呆啦
All right! All right! You're bad! Okay!
看 阿菲 这没什么了不起的
See, Phil? That... That wasn't so hard.
小子 小子
Kid, kid, kid.
你看到几只角?
How many horns do ya see?
六只
Six?
哦 差不多 我扶你起来
Close enough. Let's get you cleaned up.
别急 别急 放轻松
Guys, guys, relax.
现在是中场休息
It's only half-time.
这不是好兆头
That doesn't sound good.
真的不是好兆头
Definitely not good!
你可不可以不要再砍它的头啦
Will you forget the head-slicing thing?
阿菲 这一招你怎么从来没有教过我?
Phil, I don't think we covered this one in basic training!
游戏的最高潮
My favourite part of the game,
杀死对手
sudden death.
哦 我又失败了 就像阿奇利斯
There goes another one. Just like Achilles.
比赛
Game.
到此
Set.
结束
Match.
阿菲 你得承认啊 我表现得很棒吧
Phil, you gotta admit. That was pretty heroic.
你成功了 小子 没错 你赢得太漂亮了
Ya did it, kid! Ya did it! You won by a landslide!
凯帝斯疯了
Hades mad.
哇 真没想到
Well, what do ya know?
从这天起 大家都喜欢海格力斯
From that day forward, our boy Hercules could do no wrong.
他大受欢迎 他好酷哦
He was so hot, steam looked cool.
哦 耶
Oh, yeah
看战神不停在转动
Bless my soul Herc was on a roll
希腊民意调查 他是风云大人物
Person of the week in every Greek opinion poll
- 他能够  - 掌握这世界
- What a pro - Herc could stop a show
打击罪犯 为民除害 从不落人后
Point him at a monster and you're talkin' SRO
- 他默默无闻  - 狗熊 狗熊
- He was a no one - A zero, zero
- 变成了英雄  - 变成了英雄
- Now he's a honcho - He's a hero
他的完美会让你倾倒
Here was a kid with his act down pat
从狗熊变英雄 一瞬间
Zero to hero in no time flat
- 从狗熊变英雄  - 就这样
- Zero to hero - Just like that
那微笑会让女孩叫
When he smiled the girls went wild
呜 天
With oohs and aahs
他英俊脸庞刻在花瓶
And they slapped his face on every vase
哦 到处有
On every "vahse"
靠潇洒外表
From appearance fees and royalties
就可让他吃穿永远不愁
Our Herc had cash to burn
而突然之间名利双收
Now nouveau riche and famous
他已拥有全世界
He could tell you what's a Grecian urn
说"阿门" 他就会出现
Say amen, there he goes again
- 他是那么神气  - 不得不爱他
- Sweet and undefeated - And an awesome 10-for-10
海格力斯商场
排好队 只为看到他
Folks lined up just to watch him flex
看那发达漂亮胸肌你我都想捏
And this perfect package packed a pair of pretty pecs
海格威风 你已被征服
Hercie, he comes he sees, he conquers
他的风采更叫人崩溃
Honey, the crowds were goin' bonkers
他智勇双全又大胆
He showed the moxie brains and spunk
耶
Yeah
- 从狗熊变英雄  - 称霸天下
- From zero to hero - A major hunk
- 从狗熊变英雄  - 谁能够?
- Zero to hero - And who'd have thunk?
谁在斗剑时带来快乐?
Who put the glad in gladiator?
海格力斯
Hercules
谁的人生像是一出戏?
Who's darin' deeds are great theatre?
海格力斯
Hercules
- 他勇敢  - 无人能比
- Isn't he bold? - No one braver
- 他善良  - 是我们最爱
- Is he sweet? - Our favourite flavour
海格力斯
Hercules
My man.
- 海格力斯  - 海格力斯
- Hercules - Hercules
海格力斯
Hercules
- 海格力斯  - 海格力斯
- Hercules - Look at my Hercules
- Hercules, Hercules - Yeah, yeah, yeah
保佑我走上成功路
Bless my soul, Herc was on a roll
- 他有神力  - 飞得高
- Undefeated - Riding high
永远不会老
And the nicest guy.
他讲义气
Not conceited
- 他默默无闻  - 狗熊 狗熊
- He was a nothing - Zero, zero
- 变成了英雄  - 英雄 英雄
- Now he's a honcho - He's our hero
他的成功无人能比
He hit the heights at breakneck speed
从狗熊变英雄
From zero to hero
海格是个英雄
Herc is a hero
他是个英雄
Now he's a hero
对 没错
Yes, indeed
丢
Pull!
打得还真准啊
Nice shootin', Rex.
到底怎么回事?
I can't believe this guy.
我想尽办法要杀他 居然让他逃走了
I throw everything I've got at him and it doesn't even...
这是什么东西?
What are those?
我不知道 我只是觉得蛮好看的
I don't know. I thought they looked kinda dashing.
为了要解决这个小子 我真的是绞尽了脑汁
I've got 24 hours to get rid of this bozo,
否则我十八年的辛苦经营 就要泡汤了
or the entire scheme I've been setting up for 18 years goes up in smoke,
而你 居然还穿着他的拖鞋
and you are wearing his merchandise!
口渴吗?
Thirsty?
好像神奇小子
Looks like your game's over.
把你所有的计划都打乱了
Wonderboy is hitting every curve you throw at him.
哦 是啊
Yeah.
我在想 或许
I wonder if maybe
我该让他尝点甜头 对不对 蜜儿小宝贝?
I haven't been throwing the right curves at him, Meg, my sweet.
哼 别想打我的主意啊
Don't even go there.
他一定会有弱点 因为每一个人都有个弱点
See, he's gotta have a weakness because everybody's got a weakness.
比方说 潘朵拉 败在她的好奇心上
I mean, for what? Pandora, it was the box thing.
而特洛城就败在那个木马上 对不对?
For the Trojans, hey. They bet on the wrong horse, okay?
我们一定要找出他的弱点
We simply need to find out Wonderboy's.
我的任务已经完成 叫那两个小鬼去啊
I've done my part. Get your little imps...
他们的智商还没有发育
They couldn't handle him as a baby.
我需要你把他当个男人
I need somebody who can handle him as a man.
喂 我不会出卖我的色相
Hey, I've sworn off manhandling.
这很好啊 这不正是你当初栽在我手里的原因吗?
That's good because that's what got you into this jam in the first place.
你为了救你男朋友的性命 把自己的灵魂卖给我
You sold your soul to me to save your boyfriend's life.
但那个负心汉 是怎么报答你的?
And how does this creep thank you?
他跟别的女人跑了
By running off with some babe.
这是你唯一的机会哦
He hurt you real bad, didn't he, Meg?
听好 我已经得到教训 可以吗?
Look, I learned my lesson, okay?
所以说啦 我更觉得你该跟我合作
Which is exactly why I got a feelin' you're gonna leap at my new offer.
你只要替我找到 打倒神奇小子的方法
You give me the key to bringing down Wonder Breath,
我就给你全宇宙你最想... 最最渴望的东西
and I give you the thing that you crave most in the entire cosmos,
你的自由
your freedom.
你都没有看到 爸爸
You should have been there, Father.
我把人马兽砍成碎片 抓住三姐妹妖怪
I mangled the Minotaur, grappled with the Gorgon.
就像阿菲教的那样
Just like Phil told me.
我分析状况 控制我的力量 然后出手
I analysed the situation, controlled my strength and kicked.
群众都疯狂啦
The crowds went wild!
谢谢 谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
你真有本事啊 儿子
You're doin' great, son. You're doing your old man proud.
很高兴你这么说 爸
I'm glad to hear you say that, Father.
我等这一天已经等了好久了
I've been waiting for this day a long time.
嗯 你在等哪一天啊?
What day is that, son?
能够回到天上的这一天哪
The day I rejoin the gods.
你表现得很好 真的很优秀
You've done wonderfully. You really have, my boy.
但是你还差了那么一点点
You're just not there yet.
你没有证明你是真正的英雄
You haven't proven yourself a true hero.
但 爸爸 我把所有我遇见的怪物都打败了
But, Father, I've beaten every single monster I've come up against.
我... 我... 我是全希腊最有名的人
I-I'm-I'm the most famous person in all of Greece.
我... 我是武打天王啊
I'm-l-I'm an action figure!
我认为有名的人 并不一定是真正的英雄
I'm afraid being famous isn't the same as being a true hero.
那我该怎么做呢?
What more can I do?
这得靠你自己去发现才行
It's something you have to discover for yourself.
- 那我应该  - 用心灵去寻找
- But how can I... - Look inside your heart.
爸爸 等等
Father, wait!
在你左边是海格力斯的家
On your left is Hercules' villa.
下一站是"健美胸肌"特卖店
Our next stop is the Pecs and Flex Gift Shop
你可以购买
where you can pick up
大英雄的有氧体操实用手册 书名是《铜墙铁肌》
the great hero's 30-minute workout scroll Buns of Bronze.
一点钟 跟奥格亚斯王开会
At 1:00, you got a meeting with King Augeas.
他牛棚里有陈年牛粪
He's got a problem with his stables.
你最好不要穿新鞋
I'd advise you not to wear your new sandals.
- 阿菲  - 拜托你不要乱动
- Phil? - I told you, don't move!
与希腊女子爱国党有约
DGR, the Daughters of the Greek Revolution.
- 阿菲  -三点钟
- Phil. - At 3:00,
要接见亚马逊女战士
you gotta get a girdle from some Amazons.
阿菲 到底在搞什么嘛
Phil, what's the point?
我受够了
That's it!
有点耐性嘛 朋友
Keep your toga on, pal.
你在说什么"我在搞什么啊"?
What d'you mean, "What's the point?"
你不是想去奥林帕斯山吗?
You wanna go to Olympus, don't ya?
做这些事情对我没有帮助啊
Yeah, but this stuff doesn't seem to be getting me anywhere.
我全靠你了 你不能放弃啊
You can't give up now. I'm countin' on ya.
我已经拼命在做了
I gave this everything I had.
听我说 小子 我阅人无数
Listen to me, kid. I seen 'em all.
凭良心说 你有别人所没有的天赋
And I am tellin' you, and this is the honest-to-Zeus truth,
- 我没有见过像你这种人啊  - 真的啊?
- you got somethin' I never seen before. - Really?
我的直觉非常强烈地告诉我
I can feel it right down to these stubby bowlegs of mine.
只要你愿意 没有你做不到的
There is nothin' you can't do, kid.
是他啊
It's him!
喂 喂 小心 小心
Hey, watch it! Watch it! Watch...
- 我碰到他的手了  - 把它还给我
- I touched his elbow! - I got his sweatband!
阿菲 救命
Phil, help!
- 我一吹哨你就闪  - 知道了
- Okay. Escape plan, beta. - Gotcha.
他人呢?
Hey. Where is he?
他往那边去了 在阳台 快呀
There he goes! On the veranda!
让我猜猜看
Let's see.
是谁躲在一号帘子的后面啊
What could be behind curtain number one?
蜜儿
Meg!
没事了 那些怀春少女都走了
It's all right. The sea of raging hormones has ebbed.
哇 我真高兴遇见你
Gee, i-i-it's great to see you.
我... 我很想你
I-I-I missed you.
英雄都是这么打发时间的啊
So this is what heroes do on their days off.
我才不是英雄
I'm no hero.
你当然是 全希腊的人
Sure ya are. Everybody in Greece
都认为你是空前绝后的大英雄
thinks you're the greatest thing since they put the pocket in pitta.
我知道 实在很疯狂
I know, it's... it's crazy.
走到哪儿都被包围
You know, I can't go anywhere without being mobbed.
- 我...  - 你应该放松一下
- I mean... - You sound like you could use a break.
如果你开溜一会儿
Think your nanny goat would go berserk
你那位保姆先生会发飙吗?
if you played hooky this afternoon?
这... 我不知道啊
Oh, gee, l-I don't know.
阿菲把时间都排满了
Phil's got the rest of the day pretty much booked.
少管阿菲啊 跟我到外面走走
Phil, schmill. Just follow me.
你只要把那道墙掀起来 就可以开溜了
Out the window, round the dumbbells, you lift up the back wall and we're gone.
哇 真棒
What a day.
《俄狄浦斯王》(Oedipus Rex)：公元前5世纪索福克勒斯(Sophocles)所著的悲剧
我们先去码头餐厅吃饭 然后再去看那出 那部《奥迪帕斯》
First, that restaurant by the bay. And then that, that play, that, that, that Oedipus thing.
噢 我比他们幸福多了
Man! I thought I had problems.
- 别再闲扯 快点嘛  - 老姐 快办正事
- Stop foolin' around! - Yeah. Get the goods, sister.
真没想到开溜会这么好玩
I didn't know that playing hooky could be so much fun.
- 对 我也没想到  - 谢了 蜜儿
- Yeah. Neither did I. - Thanks, Meg.
噢 先别急着说谢
Don't thank me just yet.
小心
Careful.
抱歉 脚突然没力气
Sorry. Weak ankles.
是吗? 要不坐下来休息一会儿
Yeah? Well, maybe you better sit down for a while.
那... 你有没有像我这样子的问题啊?
So, do you have any problems with things like this?
例如 脚没力气
Weak ankles, I mean.
不 好像没有
No. Not really.
难道你没有弱点?
No weaknesses whatsoever?
你胸口疼不疼? 还有
No trick knee?
膝盖 肚子 脸蛋?
Ruptured disks?
没有 我... 我觉得... 我觉得我很健康
No. I'm, I'm, I'm afraid I'm, uh, fit as a fiddle.
神奇小子 你真的很完美
Wonderboy, you are perfect.
谢了
Thanks.
这样反而好看
It looks better that way.
真的 好看多了
No, it really does.
其实 你知道我小时候
You know, when I was a kid,
就一直希望有一天 自己能跟其他人一样
I would have given anything to be exactly like everybody else.
一样小气 不诚实吗?
You wanted to be petty and dishonest?
不是每一个人都一样的
Everybody's not like that.
都一样
Yes, they are.
你就不一样啦
You're not like that.
你怎么那么确定呢?
How do you know what I'm like?
至少我知道 你是我认识的人当中 脚最没力气的一个
All I know is you're the most amazing person with weak ankles I've ever met.
蜜儿 有了你 我一点也不觉得孤单
Meg, when I'm with you, l-I don't feel so alone.
有时候我宁愿一个人
Sometimes it's better to be alone.
为什么?
What do you mean?
没人会伤害你
Nobody can hurt you.
蜜儿
Meg?
我永远也不会伤害你
I would never, ever hurt you.
我... 我也不会伤害你 所以为了我们两个好 不能再
And I don't wanna hurt you, so let's both do ourselves a favour and stop this
这样下去
before we...
好了 停 我说停 你玩够了
All right! Break it up! Break it up! Party's over!
- 我大街小巷地找你  - 冷静点 山羊先生
- I been lookin' all over this town! - Calm down, mutton man.
这都是我的错
It was all my fault.
你已经上了我的黑名单 不受欢迎
You're already on my list, sister, so don't make it worse!
你这个没出息的东西 立刻回到体育场
And as for you, ya bum, you're gonna go to the stadium
你这一辈子都得忍受苦练
and you're gonna be put through the workout of your life!
- 快给我上马去  - 好 好
- Now get on the horse. - Okay, okay.
- 真对不起  - 没事了
- I'm sorry. - He'll get over it.
快 快 快 快 快 上马
Move! Move, move, move, move, move! Move!
小心 小心 小心 睁大你的眼睛看
Hey, watch it, watch it! Watch it! Keep your goo-goo eyes on the...
严重违规要受罚
That's it. Next time, I drive.
我到底有什么毛病?
What's the matter with me?
我怎么还控制不了感情呢?
You'd think a girl would learn.
百般思绪 涌上我心田
If there's a prize for rotten judgement
失去主张 乱了方向
I guess I've already won that
没有人不顾生命危险
No man is worth the aggravation
这痛苦的教训无力承受
That's ancient history been there, done that
不要再有假装 他是你的宇宙天堂
Who d'ya think you're kidding? He's the Earth and heaven to you
不要隐瞒躲藏你的真情 散发力量
Try to keep it hidden. Honey, we can see right through you
- 不能够  - 快把感情释放
- Oh, no - Girl, you can't conceal it
我们明白你对爱情的渴望
We know how you feel and who you're thinkin' of
不能 不愿 我不想 我不说
No chance, no way. I won't say it, no, no
轻声叹息 你为何在摇头?
You swoon, you sigh. Why deny it?
多么迷惘 我已经爱上他
It's too cliché, I won't say I'm in love
那心底深情 早已黯淡
I thought my heart had learned its lesson
再回首 满心又期待
It feels so good when you start out
前尘往事在对我呐喊
My head is screaming "Get a grip, girl"
我心凄凉无奈 泪已哭干
Unless you're dyin' to cry your heart out
你在自我否定 没有勇气追求爱情
You keep on denying who you are and how you're feelin'
我们不会相信 我们看到你的真情
Baby, we're not buyin'. Hon, we saw you hit the ceilin'
面对这份感情 你要拿出你的勇气
Face it like a grown-up when you gonna own up that you
- 快  - 快  - 快追寻
- Got - Got - Got it bad
不能 不愿 我不想 我不说
No chance, no way. I won't say it, no, no
- 打开心扉  - 你已经爱上他
- Give up, but give in - Check the grin, you're in love
此情此景 我不能爱上他
This scene won't play I won't say I'm in love
情愫决堤
You're doing flips. Read our lips
你已经爱上他
You're in love
无可救药 我不愿意
You're way off base. I won't say I'm it
她不愿意啦
She won't say in love
承受煎熬 我不愿意
Get off my case, I won't say it
抛开烦恼多美妙 爱上他
Girl, don't be proud It's okay, you're in love
对天祈祷
At least out loud
我已经爱上
I won't say I'm in
他
Love
嘿 蜜儿宝贝 还顺利吗?
Hey, what's the buzz, Meg?
你到底有没有查出神奇小子的弱点呢?
What is the weak link in Wonderboy's chain?
找别的女人去查吧 我不干了
Get yourself another girl. I'm through.
麻烦你再说一遍
I'm sorry. Do you mind runnin' that by me again?
我的耳朵好像被什么东西给堵住了
I must have had a chunk of brimstone wedged in my ear or something.
那你最好给我听清楚 我不干了
Then read my lips! Forget it.
蜜儿 蜜儿 哎哟 我亲爱的心肝小宝贝
Meg, Meg, Meg, my sweet, deluded little minion.
我们是不是已经忘了一件很小 但又非常非常重要的事情呢?
Aren't we forgetting one teensy-weensy, but ever so crucial little, tiny detail?
你是我的
I own you!
- 哦 我又多了一个角  - 你在替我工作
- I got another horn here. - You work for me.
我要罚这小子跑步一个月
That kid's gonna be doin' laps for a month.
我叫你唱歌 你就得唱歌
If I say, "Sing," you say, "Hey, name that tune."
当我要你把神奇小子的头提来见我 这时候你就得问
If I say, "I want Wonderboy's head on a platter," you say...
请问要几分熟?
Medium or well-done.
我就说那个女人是祸水 这会让那小子心碎的
I knew that dame was trouble. This is gonna break the kid's heart.
- 我会看着办的  - 你听见了吗?
- I'll work on that. - I'm sorry. You hear that sound?
那是你自由的呼声 可惜它永远地离开了
That's the sound of your freedom fluttering out the window forever.
我根本不在乎 也不会帮你去伤害他
I don't care. I'm not gonna help you hurt him.
我真是不敢相信 你居然这么不信任一个男人
I can't believe you're getting so worked up about some guy.
这个男人不一样 他很诚实 又贴心
This one is different. He's honest, and he's sweet...
少来了
Please!
- 他绝不会作任何事来伤害我  - 他是男人啊
- He would never do anything to hurt me. - He's a guy!
况且 哦 全能的神 你打不倒他的
Besides, O oneness, you can't beat him.
他是一个完全没有弱点的人 他有...
He has no weaknesses. He's gonna...
我说过 他有弱点
I think he does, Meg.
我会把他的弱点挖出来
I truly think he does.
喂 阿菲 你去哪儿了?
Hey, Phil! What happened to you?
小子 我有话要跟你说
Kid, we gotta talk.
阿菲啊 今天是我生命里最棒的一天
Phil, I just had the greatest day of my life!
我无法不想蜜儿
I, I, I can't stop thinkin' about Meg.
她真是特别
She's something else.
小子 我有话跟你说 你静一下好吗?
Kid, I'm tryin' to talk to ya! Will you come down here and listen?
我开心呆了 我怎么静得下来呢?
How can I come down there when I'm feeling so up?
抓到了
Gotcha!
很好 我想告诉你的是
Very nice! What I'm tryin' to say is...
如果没有你 我也不会遇见她
That if it wasn't for you, I never would have met her.
我欠你一个大人情
I owe you big time.
放我下来 你可不可以先听我说嘛
Will you just knock it off for a couple of seconds?
规则三十八 把拳头举起来
ule number 38. Come on, Phil. Keep them up there, huh?
- 我只有一句话 看招  - 听我说 她是
- Phil, I got two words for ya, duck! - Listen to me! She's...
- 实现梦想  - 不是啦
- A dream come true? - Not exactly.
- 比维纳斯还要美丽  - 美的相反
- More beautiful than Aphrodite? - Aside from that!
- 她是最棒的  - 她是... 她是骗子
- The most wonderful... - She's a... She's a fraud!
她把你当成呆鸟在玩弄
She's been playin' ya for a sap!
- 拜托 你少骗我了  - 我没有骗你
- Come on. Stop kiddin' around. - I'm not kiddin' around.
我今天的表现让你生气 但是
I know you're upset about today, but that's no reason to...
小子 你没说到重点
Kid, you're missin' the point.
- 重点是我爱她  - 她不爱你
- The point is, I love her. - She don't love you.
- 你神经病  - 她一点都不可靠
- You're crazy. - She's nothin' but a two-timin'...
- 够了  - 不道德 骗子 人渣
- Stop it! - No-good, lyin', schemin'...
闭嘴
Shut up!
阿菲 我...
Phil. I...
对不起 我...
I'm sorry.
好 好 算了 你不愿意面对 那就算了
Okay, okay, that's it. You won't face the truth? Fine.
阿菲 等等 你要去哪儿?
Phil, wait. Where you going?
我要搭第一班船离开 回老家去
I'm hoppin' the first barge out of here. I'm goin' home.
好啊
Fine!
你走啊 反正我也不需要你
Go! I don't... I don't need you.
我以为你是超越一切的冠军
I thought you were gonna be the all-time champ,
而不是一个大笨蛋
not the all-time chump.
天哪 谁惹他生这么大的气啊?
Geez Louise! What got his goat, huh?
我是死亡大帝凯帝斯
Name is Hades, Lord of the Dead.
- 你好  - 别烦我 好不好?
- Hi. How ya doin'? - Not now, okay?
唉 只需要几秒钟 我的速度很快的
Hey, hey. I only need a few seconds and I'm a fast talker, all right?
我有一笔重要的交易 希望我能够说得清楚
I've got the major deal in the works. A real estate venture, if you will.
海格 我能够叫你海格吗?
And Herc, you little devil you. May I call you Herc?
你一直在干扰我这笔生意 你知不知道?
You seem to be constantly getting in the way of it.
你找错人了
You've got the wrong guy.
听我说 你这... 听我说好吗?
Hear me out, ya little... Just hear me out, okay?
你可不可以暂时不要当英雄
So I would be eternally grateful
只要一天就够了 我会永远感激你
if you would just take a day off from this hero business of yours.
忘掉什么怪物啦 天灾人祸啦 他们可以等你
I mean, monsters, natural disasters. You wait a day, okay?
- 你疯了你  - 别这样嘛 我心里有个人
- You're out of your mind. - Not so fast, because, ya see,
或许你会对她有兴趣 你考虑考虑
I do have a little leverage you might wanna know about.
- 蜜儿  - 别听他的
- Meg! - Don't listen, Herc...
- 放了她  - 这是交换的条件
- Let her go! - Here's the trade-off.
你只要答应 放弃你的力气二十四小时
You give up your strength for about 24 hours, okay?
从现在起二十四小时
Say the next 24 hours.
蜜儿就会像鸟一样地自由
And Meg here is free as a bird and safe from harm.
跳舞 唱歌 聊天 喝茶 爱干什么就干什么
We dance, we kiss, we schmooze, we carry on, we go home happy.
怎么样?
What d'ya say? Come on.
老百姓可能会受伤 对不对?
People are gonna get hurt, aren't they?
不会 也许吧 有可能 天灾人祸嘛
Nah! I mean, it's a possibility. It happens 'cause, you know, it's war.
谁也没办法预料 你干嘛那么担心?
But what can I tell ya? Anyway, what do you owe these people?
难道你就不担心 甜甜的蜜儿吗?
Isn't Meg, little smoochy face, isn't she more important than they are?
- 别说了  - 不是吗?
- Stop it! - Isn't she?
你必须发誓 她不会受到任何伤害
You've gotta swear she'll be safe from any harm.
好 没问题 我可以发誓
Fine, okay. I'll give you that one.
蜜儿很安全 否则你就可以
Meg is safe, otherwise you get your strength right back.
重新得到你的力气了 这样总可以了吧?
Fine print. Boilerplate. Okay? Done. What d'ya say we shake on it?
我没有太多时间浪费在这儿
Hey, I really don't have, like, time to bat this around.
我有时间上的压力 你得马上
I'm kind of on a schedule here. I got plans for August. Okay?
给我做一个决定 一秒钟 两秒钟
I need an answer, like, now. Going once, going twice...
- 我答应  - 好极了 成交
- All right! - Yes, we're there!
你可能会觉得有一点恶心 不过这是正常的
You may feel just a little queasy. It's kinda natural.
或许你该先坐下
Maybe you should sit down!
现在你总算了解 当个平凡人是什么滋味了吧
Now you know how it feels to be just like everybody else.
不也挺棒的吗? 笨蛋
Isn't it just peachy?
哦 还有一件事情
You'll love this. One more thing.
蜜儿宝贝 在商言商 你已经自由了
Meg, babe, a deal's a deal. You're off the hook.
忘了告诉你 这个小妞是一个很好的演员
And by the way, Herc, is she not a fabulous little actress?
- 别说了  - 什么意思?
- Stop it. - What do you mean?
意思就是你的小女友 一直在替我工作 呆子
I mean your little chickie-poo here was working for me all the time.
你... 你在骗我
You're... You're lying!
- 救命  - 天哪 先生 你真的好壮喔
- Help! - Jeepers, mister, you're really strong.
没有你 我真的做不到 蜜儿宝贝
Couldn't have done it without you, sugar, sweetheart, babe.
不 事情不是这样
No! It's not like that.
我不是故意要... 我没有办法 我...
I didn't mean to... I couldn't... I...
我对不起你
I'm so sorry.
英雄变狗熊 英雄变狗熊
Our hero's a zero! Our hero's a zero!
好 该走了
Well, gotta blaze.
整个宇宙正等着我去掌管呢 噢 对了 小笨蛋
There's a whole cosmos up there waiting for me with, hey, my name on it.
下次再有人叫你白痴 疯子 千万别怀疑
So much for the preliminaries, and now on to the main event!
兄弟们 泰坦巨魔
Brothers! Titans!
看看这个关你们肮脏的地狱
Look at you in your squalid prison!
是谁把你们关在这里的?
Who put you down there?
宙斯
Zeus!
如果我让你们自由 你们第一件想做的事是什么?
And now that I set you free, what is the first thing you are going to do?
- 摧毁宙斯  - 答得好
- Destroy him! - Good answer.
压碎宙斯
Crush Zeus!
摧毁他
Freeze him!
摧毁宙斯
Melt Zeus!
摧毁他
Blow him away!
宙斯
Zeus!
对不起 各位
Guys?
奥林帕斯山在后面
Olympus would be that way.
- 宙斯  - 摧毁宙斯
- Zeus! - Freeze him!
等等 大眼睛
Hold it, bright eye.
有个特别的任务要交给你 嘿 独眼龙啊
I have a special job for you, my optic friend.
摧毁宙斯
Destroy Zeus!
麻烦来了 大祸临头
We're in trouble! Big trouble! I gotta...
我的主人 泰坦巨魔越狱
My lord and lady, the Titans have escaped,
他们就快要上来了
and they're practically at our gates!
快开警报器 立刻准备反攻
Sound the alarm! Launch an immediate counterattack!
- 快 快啊  - 遵命
- Go! Go! - Gone, babe.
冲锋
Charge!
上战场了
On to battle!
好大的风啊
You windbag!
海格力斯
Hercules!
你在哪里?
Where are you?
我们该怎么办?
What can we do?
- 海格力斯人呢?  - 对啊 海格力斯会救我们的
- Where is Hercules? - Yeah, Hercules'll save us.
海格力斯
Hercules!
快出来 战斗
Come out! Face me!
你要干什么? 你已经没有力气 你会死的
What are you doing? Without your strength, you'll be killed.
我管不了那么多了
There are worse things.
跑吧
Run!
等等 你别去
Wait! Stop!
- 看 海格力斯来了  - 感谢众神
- Hey, look! It's Hercules. - Thank the gods!
- 我们有救了  - 那
- We're saved! - So...
你就是伟大的海格力斯啊
You mighty Hercules.
乖 乖 别动 你听话
Easy, horsefeathers.
你别再踢了
Stop twitching.
海格力斯有难了
Listen. Hercules is in trouble.
我们去找阿菲
We've gotta find Phil.
只有他才能说服海格力斯
He's the only one who can talk some sense into him.
过来 我炸死你
Get back, blast you!
- 有得瞧了  - 宙斯
- Chihuahua. - Zeus!
来啊 快啊 快离开这儿
Come on! Hurry up! We're shovin' off here!
阿菲
Phil!
海格力斯他需要你
Phil, Hercules needs your help!
他有了你这个朋友 怎么还会需要我?
What does he need me for when he's got friends like you?
- 他不听我的话  - 很好 他总算得到教训了
- He won't listen to me. - Good! He's finally learned something.
拜托 我知道是我错了 但这不是为了我
Look, I know what I did was wrong, but this isn't about me.
是为了他 如果你不帮他 他会死的
It's about him. If you don't help him now, Phil, he'll die.
我需要更多闪电
I need more thunderbolts!
你闪电的火神被抓住了 主人
Hephaestus has been captured, my lord.
大家都被抓住了 我也被抓住了
Everyone's been captured. I've been captured!
小心我的眼镜
Hey, hey! Watch the glasses.
宙斯 我回来咯
Zeusy, I'm home!
凯帝斯 果然是你搞的鬼
Hades. You're behind this!
你说得对 大人
You are correct, sir!
出局
Flea.
- 海格力斯  - 阿菲
- Hercules! - Phil.
加油 小子 加油 反击
Come on, kid. Come on. Fight back.
很好对付的 那个肥仔不堪一击
Come on, you can take this bum. This guy's a pushover. Look at him.
你说得没错 阿菲
You were right all along, Phil.
菜鸟不配做梦
Dreams are for rookies.
不不不 小子 菜鸟才会放弃
No, no, no, no, kid. Givin' up is for rookies.
我回来是因为我没有放弃你
I came back 'cause I'm not quittin' on ya.
我愿意坚持到底
I'm willing to go the distance.
你怎么样?
How 'bout you?
咬断你的头
Me bite off head!
加油 小子
Whoa, baby!
海格力斯 小心
Hercules! Look out!
蜜儿 不
Meg! No!
怎么会这样?
What's happening?
凯帝斯的交易失效了
Hades' deal is broken.
他说我绝对不会受伤的
He promised I wouldn't get hurt.
蜜儿
Meg.
你... 你为什么?
Why... why... why did ya...
你... 为什么这么做?
You didn't have to...
恋爱中的男孩女孩 都会很疯狂
People always do crazy things when they're in love.
蜜儿
Meg.
蜜儿 我... 我...
Meg, I... I...
你... 平常都是这么说话的?
Are you always this articulate?
时间已经不多了 快去阻止凯帝斯
You... You haven't got much time. You can still stop Hades.
我来照顾她
I'll watch over her, kid.
你不会有事的
You're gonna be all right.
我保证
I promise.
来吧 柏格斯
Let's go, Pegasus!
一 二 三 四 大家跟着我念
Hup, two, three, four. Come on, everybody!
我听不见
I can't hear you!
我发誓 凯帝斯 只要我一脱离
I swear to you, Hades, when I get out of this...
现在由我来发号施令 闪电小子
I'm the one giving orders now, bolt boy.
而且我非常喜欢这里
And I think I'm gonna like it here.
你好日子不多了 凯帝斯
Don't get too comfortable, Hades!
海格力斯
Hercules!
我来救你们了
This ought to even the odds!
好耶 海格力斯 谢谢你
Yeah, Hercules! Thank you, man.
抓住他
Get them!
嘿
Hey!
是他 不是我 是他
No! Get him! Not me! Him!
我手指的这一个 还有他的马
Follow the fingers! Him! The yutz with the horse.
谢了 儿子
Thank you, my boy.
别跟着我 不是我 不是我 你饶了我吧
Nice horsey! My intentions were pure! I really was attracted to you.
接着
Throw!
该我大显神威啦
Now watch your old man work!
快把泰坦巨魔撤离这里 离开奥林帕斯山
Guys, get your titanic rears in gear and kick some Olympian butt!
我的假发掉了吗?
Is my hair out?
你狠 神奇小子
Thanks a ton, Wonderboy.
但是别忘了我还有个纪念品
But at least I've got one swell consolation prize,
你的小宝贝蜜儿正在地狱等着见我
a friend of yours who's dying to see me.
蜜儿
Meg.
蜜儿 不
Meg, no.
对不起 小子
I'm sorry, kid.
有些事情你无法改变
There's some things you just can't change.
我可以
Yes, I can.
就差一点点
We were so close!
就这一点点
So close.
真是马前失蹄 为什么呢?
We tripped at the finish line. Why?
因为我的小蜜儿 突然变得有良心了
Because our little nut, Meg, has to go all noble.
- 蜜儿在哪里?  - 瞧瞧谁来了
- Where's Meg? - Look who's here.
你可真了不起啊
Wonderboy, you are too much.
- 快放人  - 好大的口气啊
- Let her go. - Get a grip.
来来来 我带你逛逛
Come here, come here. Let me show you around.
来瞧瞧啊 我精致的死亡深渊
Well, well. It's a small underworld after all. Huh?
蜜儿
Meg!
等等 不可以
No, no, no. Mustn't touch.
蜜儿已经有了另外一群新的同伴了
You see, Meg's running with a new crowd these days.
只是不太可爱罢了
And not a very lively one, at that.
你不是喜欢交易吗? 用我来换蜜儿
You like making deals. Take me in Meg's place.
哦 我想想看 我对手的儿子将永远沉于死亡深渊
Well. The son of my hated rival trapped forever in a river of death.
- 一秒钟  - 我会不会吃亏呢?
- Going once. - Is there a downside to this?
- 两秒钟  - 好 可以 可以 没问题
- Going twice! - Okay, okay, okay, okay.
你去把她救出来 她上来 你下去
You get her out. She goes, you stay.
我忘了告诉你
You know what slipped my mind?
你还没碰到她 你就会先死
You'll be dead before you can get to her.
有问题吗?
That's not a problem, is it?
这把剪刀是怎么啦?
What's the matter with these scissors?
这条生命之线剪不断
The thread won't cut.
这... 这怎么可能呢?
This is... This is impossible!
你... 你不可能活的 难道说你已经变成
You... You... You can't be alive! You'd have to be a...
- 神  - 神
- A god? - A god?
海格力斯 你不可以这样对我
Hercules, stop! You can't do this to me. You can't...
可以 可以
Fine. Okay. Listen.
就算是我罪有应得 海格 海格 我们谈谈
Okay. Well, I deserved that. Herc, Herc, Herc. Can we talk?
你爸爸 他人是很好的啦
Your dad, he's a fun guy, right?
这样吧 你去帮我跟他说说
So maybe you could put in a word with him,
我们这只是一场误会 到现在已经一笔勾销了
and he'd kinda blow this whole thing off, you know?
好吧 蜜儿 蜜儿宝贝 你醒醒
Meg, Meg, talk to him. A little schmooze...
滚开 滚开 离我远一点 你们的脏手 哎呦 恶心死了
Get away from me! Don't touch me! Get your slimy souls off me!
如果他能好好享受 在里面一定很开心
He's not gonna be happy when he gets outta there.
- 你是说"如果" 如果的话  - 计程车
- You mean, if he gets outta there. - Taxi!
- 对 "如果"是个好词  - 计程车
- If. If is good. - Taxi!
这一点都不好玩 我玩完了
I don't feel so good. I feel a little...
神奇小子 你...
Wonderboy, what...
为什么?
Why did you...
恋爱中的男孩女孩
People always do crazy things
都会比较疯狂
when they're in love.
喂 喂 喂
Hey, hey, hey!
为伟大的海格力斯欢呼三声
Three cheers for the mighty Hercules!
哦 是啊 每个人都献花
Yeah! Flowers for everybody!
海格力斯 我们都以你为荣
Hercules, we're so proud of you.
妈
Mother.
干得好 儿子 你成功了
Fine work, my boy! You've done it!
你是真正的英雄
You're a true hero.
你愿意为了救这个女孩子 而牺牲自己的生命
You were willing to give your life to rescue this young woman.
真正的英雄 不是用力气的大小来衡量
For a true hero isn't measured by the size of his strength,
而是以心灵的力量来衡量的
but by the strength of his heart.
现在 我的儿子啊
Now, at last, my son,
你可以回家了
you can come home.
恭喜你了 神奇小子 你会是个很了不起的神
Congratulations, Wonderboy. You'll make one heck of a god.
爸爸 这是我梦寐已久的时刻
Father, this is the moment I've always dreamed of.
但是
But...
我的生命如果没有蜜儿 就算我成了神
A life without Meg, even an immortal life,
也是空虚
would be empty.
我
I...
我希望跟她待在凡间
I wish to stay on Earth with her.
我找到属于我的地方了
I finally know where I belong.
唱歌吧 女士们
Hit it, ladies!
- 登上高山 我们大声唱  - 新星闪亮
- Gonna shout it from the mountaintops - A star is born
- 我们开酒庆祝 好舒畅  - 新星闪亮
- It's the time for pulling out the stops - A star is born
- 你我相偎相依 真情流露  - 海格光芒万丈
- Honey, hit us with a hallelu - That kid came shining through
光芒万丈
Girl, sing the song
- 号角作响  - 新星闪亮
- Come blow your horn - A star is born
- 他是万民英雄 不骄傲  - 新星闪亮
- He's a hero who can please the crowd - A star is born
大家心手相携 大声喊 新星闪亮
Come on, everybody shout out loud. A star is born
当你垂头丧气 很懊恼 发挥心灵的力量
Just remember in the darkest hour within your heart's the power
让每一个人成为英雄
For makin' you a hero, too
如果沮丧 怀疑 困惑
So don't lose hope when you're forlorn
那是阿菲的徒弟
That's Phil's boy!
张大双眼 仰望星空
Just keep your eyes upon the skies
就在每个黑夜 你一定会发现 灿烂的新星闪亮
Every night, a star is right in sight, a star is
- 满天光芒 满布那黑夜  - 新星闪亮
- Burning bright, a star is born - A star is born
【海盗影院  出品】
-== http://www.hdmeiju.com ==-
新浪微博: @海盗美剧
你们来给我评评理啊 这是什么世界嘛
What d'ya say? It's happy ending time!
每个人都开开心心的
Everybody's got a little taste of somethin' but me.
只有我什么都没捞到 白玩了一场
I got nothin'. I'm here with nothin'. Anybody listenin'?
哎 有人在吗? 这算什么嘛
It's like I'm... What am I, an echo or something?
哈啰 哈啰 这是哪儿啊? 外太空啊 哈啰 不理算了
Hello? Hello? Am I talking to, what? Hyperspace? Hello, it's me.